This is Miami, Florida, a city that's
becoming the most [music] powerful money
hub in all of America. Old money to new
money, millionaires to billionaires,
everyone says Miami is the land of
opportunity. So, I came to Miami to meet
the people running the city and figure
out how they actually built their
wealth. In this video, I'm meeting
[music] everyone from The Wolf of Wall
Street to the owner of a $100 million
compound [music] to understand how real
wealth is actually built in today's
world.
Sir, how did you get rich?
How did you get rich? I grew up with a
channel of 20 million followers. I'm not
rich.
You found the wrong guy. All right, I'm
sorry.
Excuse me, sir.
I had a question for you, sir. How did
you get rich?
What's that? Hey, no, real quick, sir. I
I grew up with a channel of 20 million
followers.
Excuse me, sir. How old were you when
you became a millionaire?
What makes you think I'm a millionaire?
Man, I've been Googled for 40 billion in
the last I grew up with a channel of 21
million followers. Let me help him in.
They want to know how you became a
millionaire. I'm not a millionaire.
He's a billionaire.
Can I just ask one question, sir? If you
had one advice to the younger generation
of entrepreneurs,
I don't want to be I'm not going to be
filmed. Wait, can you just give one
piece of advice to the younger
generation on how to be successful?
>> No. You know how I became successful? By
doing what I want to do and this is not
what I want to do. All right, you guys,
look, as you can see, man, I tried, man.
I tried to fight for that interview
right there. And shout out to his
daughter, the ladies that he was with,
man, they tried to get him to stop
gatekeeping and give some game. If only
that billionaire knew how impactful his
advice could have been for the younger
generation. But look, I'm not going to
let that discourage me. I don't care how
many no's I get in this video. Look,
every no is a step closer to yes, so I'm
not going to stop until I go find the
real millionaires and billionaires that
live out here in Miami. You guys, come
on. All right, you guys, look, we're in
the design district right now. There's
more supercars here than anywhere else
in the world than maybe other than like
Dubai, but anyways, look, we got a
Rolls-Royce that's backing in right now
to the valet. We're going to go up and
try to interview them figure out how
they got Rolls-Royce rich out here in
Miami. You guys come on.
Excuse me, sir. Excuse me, sir. Sir. Is
this your Rolls-Royce? Yeah. And how did
you get rich?
>> One minute. Two minutes, guys. Okay,
sure. Thank you, man. How How did you
get rich? Uh
sold my sold a business. I worked at a
business was super successful and then
sold it. How much did you sell it? Real
quick, sir. I know there are
billionaires all over the world. How
much did you sell your company for?
>> Well, the I sold it twice. The first
time I sold it, I sold it for over 100
million and the second time I sold it,
took on new partners, took on a big
management systems and we sold it again
for over 400 million.
>> 400 million dollars. Yeah. Could I
interview you for a minute real quick?
Is that okay? Yeah, sure.
>> What type of company did you sell?
>> It was a food distribution business. I
bought it for 300,000. Very small, few
employees, but you know, I built a great
team around me, smartest guys out there,
hardest working, super loyal.
>> So, you bought the company.
>> Yeah, small little business for 300,000.
So, you turned 300,000 into 400 million
dollars. Yeah. When you say food
distribution, who are your customers?
Who are you selling to?
>> Every restaurant you go to was my
client, everyone. Actually, everyone.
There's not a restaurant that we didn't
serve.
>> How in the world did you get access to
these types of clients paying you
millions of dollars?
>> Having the right products, having the
best buying team, the best procurement
team available and also having great
sales side. We had a wonderful sales
force out there on the street and
hitting all the restaurants. Had a great
product, competitive pricing, great
service. Service is a big big factor in
our business. And then to make a long
story short, it all worked out
wonderfully.
>> You're part of the top 1%. I'm going to
challenge you right now. Where do the
richest people in the world put their
money?
>> If you have real estate, you can never
really go broke. Actually.
>> It's a sleeper. I bought a piece of real
estate for 5 million dollars back in
2013, very little cash. I'm going to say
15% so maybe 7-800,000 and that building
today is probably worth 25-30 million
dollars. Are you serious?
>> Yeah, cost base on that is very low.
>> How much real estate do you own today?
>> Over 100. 100 million dollars of it?
>> Yeah, not 100,000. Not 100,000.
>> 100
>> million dollars in it. But you can't
pull the cash out of the real estate
unless you sell it though. No, you can
refinance it and that's tax free. So
break down, what is what do you mean by
refinance? If you and I bought this
building across the street for two
million dollars and it appreciated over
a period of the next five, six years to
eight million dollars and there was a
six million dollar equity piece in here
and assuming the two million was all
debt, you would be able to leverage that
building and take out the money tax
free.
>> a couple million bucks. Yeah, you can
take out a lot more than that.
>> Hey, and you go buy some more real
estate.
>> Well, that's exactly the play. That's
the real estate game. You've sold
companies for hundreds of millions of
dollars. You got to know a thing or two
about negotiation. What's your best
negotiation advice right here?
>> The most important thing about
negotiation, the deal has to work for
both of you. If it works works for just
yourself, it won't last. If it works for
them only, you're wasting your own time.
So it's got to be win-win business. It's
got to be win-win always. Always
win-win. When people try to sell a
company like you did for hundreds of
millions of dollars, what's the number
one mistake they make?
>> They didn't structure it correctly. They
didn't create enough of a a platform
where they implemented the right process
and procedures for them to obtain the
highest valuation possible.
>> How important was the entity structure?
When you started your companies, did you
have an LLC? Like did you structure your
company?
>> absolutely.
>> How important was that?
>> important, but that's that's like
getting dressed in the morning. That has
to be done.
>> What company did you go to to start your
LLC and S corp? You can basically do
that online yourself. I had good
accountants to do it for me, but you can
do that yourself.
>> I had a billionaire tell me one time
that the reason why people fail in
business is because they don't set
themselves up for success from the
beginning. They don't have the
foundation there. Correct. So there's a
company that I've used for all of my
companies to start my businesses, all my
LLCs. It's called Bizee and it enables
you to set your business up to turn the
idea into a business in just 10 minutes.
Sure.
>> It doesn't take months. It doesn't take
days like everybody thinks it does.
Takes hours, yeah. Takes possibly 10
minutes, yeah. So that next company that
that you start, we're going to have you
go through Bizee. Absolutely. Let's do
it. I'll be setting up a new LLC
shortly. You bought a company for three
hundred thousand, turned it into four
hundred million dollars. Do you think
somebody should start or buy a business
in today's world?
>> Start. Start. Why?
>> Because I'm You bought a business, man.
And you flipped it. I didn't buy income.
I bought access to the industry. I
bought access to key employees. That's
game right there. That's game. You buy
businesses when you need access. You
build businesses when you have the
tools.
>> You got amazing advice, Hof. Right?
>> All right, my man. Listen.
>> so much for your time. Hey, I I connect
with all the billionaires I interview.
Could I get your contact? Absolutely.
>> Is that cool? Absolutely. Guys, we just
interviewed an entrepreneur [music] that
sold his company for $400 million. Man,
Miami is crazy, you guys. That's why
we're out [music] here. And what did he
say? Even after that 9-figure exit, he's
already getting ready to start that next
LLC. And that's what the most successful
entrepreneurs understand. By starting
that LLC, every idea they have can
become a real business fast. And I told
him the same thing that I tell everyone.
Look, I've observed the most successful
[music] entrepreneurs, they all use
Bizzy to start their companies.
>> Because here's the truth. People think
setting up a business is this long,
complicated process that takes months,
requires lawyers, and tons of paperwork
[music and singing] that you don't want
to touch.
>> But it doesn't. With Bizzy, you don't
need a lawyer to start your business at
all. Because they handle the filings for
you. They handle all the paperwork. They
handle the compliance. Everything you
can think of. So, you can turn your idea
into an actual LLC [music] and business
overnight, not in months or years like
everyone assumes. But here's what
setting up a business through Bizzy
really does. Having that LLC, that means
protection for your personal assets,
[music] the right structure from day
one, and a foundation that actually lets
you scale. So, if entrepreneurs who are
selling their companies for hundreds of
millions of dollars are immediately
starting their companies the smart way,
then you should, too.
>> Guys, waste no more time. Click the link
in the description of this video to
start your business through Bizzy today
and turn your idea into a real company
this week. With that being said, let's
go get this next interview. Guys, right
now I'm on the way to go meet and
interview my 41st billionaire that I've
ever interviewed since I started the
School of Hard Knocks. And it's my first
ever Cuban billionaire that I'm going to
be featuring on this channel. This is
the guy that built his wealth building
one of the biggest law firms in America,
in technology and healthcare, and a
whole bunch of different industries. And
I'm not just going to be interviewing
him anywhere. I'm going to be
interviewing him at his I don't even
want to call it an estate, but a
compound. A $175 [snorts]
million house that he owns is where
we're headed right now to go interview
with the man, John Ruiz, the 41st
billionaire in Hard Knocks history.
Let's go see what he has to say. How you
doing, sir? Good. Perfect. All right,
you guys, we are in and we are right now
and just a couple seconds going to be
approaching the house of billionaire
John Ruiz out here in Miami, Florida,
right? We're going to be interviewing
him. Like I said, guys, at his $175
million house, guys. Look, I I've been
to million dollar houses, 10 million
dollar houses. We're talking $175
million dollar houses. This is about to
be insane, you guys. Come on. All right,
you guys, we just got to the house out
here. Like I said, this is not a 10
million dollar house, a $175 million
dollar house that we're about to go into
and see, you guys. Come on.
Hello.
How are you? I'm doing good. How about
yourself?
>> Doing great.
>> for John. You ready to interview a
billionaire? Yes. Yes, this is our uh
this is our 41st one. We were just
talking about, so.
>> You're beating records.
>> Yeah, th- thank you for having us out.
>> It's a pretty big house. He's going to
be coming out here? He's going to be
coming out. How you doing, sir? How are
you? Good, man. It's great to meet you,
John. Good to meet you. Thank you for
having us out, man. Welcome. Welcome.
>> We were letting them know, man. You
know, you were the 41st billionaire that
I've interviewed on this channel.
>> I did, okay. Well. Yes, sir. Happy
you're a young guy and and doing what
you're doing. It's great great great
work.
>> Can we check out the spot?
>> Absolutely. So, how long has this been
home for?
>> I've been here about 6 years. 6 years.
Uh I bought it and then I I've done a
lot of improvements to it. For sure.
First of all, growing up, did you have
any idea? I mean, I've never seen a
walkway like this in my entire life. Did
you have any idea growing up that this
was going to be possible, man?
>> Uh no, you don't think about it, but you
know, this country's amazing. You know,
my dad was homeless, came from Cuba with
five kids, and I was the first one to
ever go to college and much less higher
education. So, I went to law school.
>> So, so you didn't come from money? No, I
came from nothing. It really started
with a $800 credit card debt that my dad
had given me with a Discover credit
card, and that's how I started back
then. Got out of law school, went
straight to open up my own firm, and I
didn't have money to pay rent, so I gave
hours of work instead of the rent.
>> So, back then, you did trade some time
for money.
>> Well, absolutely.
>> Can we check out more of the spot? Let's
go do it. Let's go check out the
backyard, shall we?
>> Let's go do it. Let's do it, my man.
What would you say is the total
valuation of this house? You know, this
is right now the most expensive
neighborhood in the United States. The
homes out here are at about 175 million
right now. I bought it for 46 million,
and I've invested probably about another
20 into it. That alone is a big
accomplishment, at least for me, you
know, because I was born in the United
States, the only one of the five kids.
Little by little, you start learning.
Here's what I can tell people. It takes
the same effort to make $1 than it does
to make 100 million.
>> [laughter]
>> It is. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> thing because the rules are the same,
the laws are the same. It's just a
bigger platform. And sometimes it's
easier because the people that you're
dealing with are at that level already,
and they understand. And they move like
that.
>> And they move quick, and they know what
they want to do, right? So, that's one
of the things you learn with time that
you don't really have to reinvent the
wheel. You just got to do what you do.
Now, innovation is different cuz to me,
that is sort of trying to create a new
wheel.
>> Let's check out the backyard, my man. Do
it.
>> [music]
>> Now, John, I got one last rule for all
my interviews. There's no holding back.
We're going to give the younger
generation the blueprint on how to
become not a millionaire, but a
billionaire in today's world. Can we
make that happen?
>> Absolutely. Let's do it. Do you think
everybody's built for entrepreneurship?
>> No, it takes a lot of dedication, hard
work, and a lot of sacrifice.
>> Did you sacrifice a lot?
>> I still do. You still do? I still do.
How old are you? 59. Do you sleep a lot?
>> No, I sleep 3 and 1/2, 4 hours a night
at most.
>> You're not Are you Are you serious?
>> I'm serious.
>> I really sleep 2 hours solid.
>> Two solid hours. You can function,
right? And I can function, right. Man, I
I don't drink, I don't do drugs, I don't
do anything that's toxic to my body. I
try to work out, train, I eat well. One
of the most important things that people
need to understand is you have to be
available. If you're not an available
person, that people call you and you
don't respond, and and it's not going to
work. I always respond to everybody. You
text message me, I'm responding to. The
emails are a little different cuz
there's so many of them. I get over a
thousand something emails a day. So, you
don't mind if I tell somebody you want
going to me. I There's not one text
message that I don't have the time that
I go to sleep or I wake up at 3:00, 4:00
in the morning, I'm responding to
everybody's text message.
>> So, being busy is not a flex.
>> No. No. No, it's not. It's just not.
>> me ask you this. Among yourself and all
the billionaires that you know, what do
they all have in common?
>> You got to believe in yourself. Yeah.
And don't listen to the noise. Every
single time I've had a business that's
been successful, everybody told me it
wasn't going to work. Everybody.
>> Why don't you listen to them?
>> Because I listen to myself. If you don't
believe in yourself, then nobody else is
going to believe in you. Right. There's
a saying that money is the root of all
evil. Do you think that money changes
people or just amplifies who you already
are?
>> I think a lot of times it changes people
because it goes to their head.
>> Did you ever let it go to your head?
>> Never. Why not? Because to me money
comes and goes. And I learned that. I've
had a lot, I've had a little, I've had
to struggle. I still remember when I
first got married, I didn't have $10 to
go to McDonald's. Money's not that
important to me. And by the way, you
know why? Because I can go sell lemons
in the corner and I'm going to make more
money than anybody else. Because I have
the drive. And I know how to do it and I
have the vision. I could lose everything
tomorrow and probably in a year or two
I'll be back.
>> What's the biggest misconception people
have about really wealthy people?
>> I think if you really divide society
into three, you have the people that are
doers and I find myself as somebody like
that. I'm not going to criticize a Jeff
Bezos, an Elon Musk, a John Morgan. Why
am I going to criticize them? But
there's people that focus on criticizing
the people that do 90% for your
community or society that are helping
the masses. They don't do anything.
These people that criticize, they just
criticize to be evil and they talk bad
about the people and most of the time
they don't even know them. They don't
even know who they are as a human being.
Why you hating? Why you hating? Because
it's envy and that's the two worst
letters in the alphabet are the N and
the V and you put them together, it's
envy.
>> But you don't worry about them. You
don't worry about their opinions. No, I
do. At first when I was younger, I did.
But now I realize like these people
don't pay my bills, they don't do
anything and at the end of the day
Nobody else's thoughts ever paid my
bills.
>> Never Never Never your bills. Now, I'm
going to challenge you right now. Take
me back to the most life-changing
conversation you ever had. What is the
greatest piece of advice you've received
throughout your career?
>> My dad. There's no bad business with a
good man. There's no good business with
a bad men. You'll never fail. Have you
ever been over in business? Million
times. Yeah? But I harder.
>> [laughter]
>> There's no mercy for the competition.
>> No, no, I don't sleep and I I will you
you'll pay. How old are you now? 59. Are
you a good negotiator? I won't say it,
but my partner says I'm the best
negotiator he's ever ever met.
>> So give me your best sales and
negotiation advice as a billionaire for
the entrepreneurs out there. You got to
make the other person understand why
what you have is valuable to them, not
valuable to you. So when you make them
understand that they need you and you
don't need them, that's when you're
going to make the best deal. Let me ask
you this, if me and you die tomorrow and
you had one last message to leave with
the younger generation, what would that
be? It's not about how great you are one
day. My dad taught me this. You got to
do it every day. One day somebody will
wake up and I want to conquer the world
and then the next day they don't do it.
I wake up every day with the same goal
in mind, which is to execute.
>> amazing advice, sir. Thank you. Thank
you for your time. By the way, I connect
with all the billionaires I interview.
Could I get your contact?
>> Absolutely. All right, guys, we just
wrapped up with the billionaire John
Ruiz at his $175 million compound out
here in Miami, Florida. He just dropped
so much game in that entire interview.
But what did he say? It takes the same
amount of stress, the same amount of
effort to solve $1 problems as it does
$10,000 problems as it does million
dollar problems and billion dollar
problems. Solve rich people problems and
you'll make way more money. Great
interview out here in Miami. Let's go
with this next one and keep this one
rolling, you guys. Come on. Guys, the
time has now come. We are right now on
the way to go meet and interview the
legend, the Wolf of Wall Street, Jordan
Belfort, at his house out here in Miami.
Jordan has one of the most iconic
business stories of all time. Look,
you've seen the movie. I've seen the
movie. I don't know how many times.
Look, this is a guy that's mastered the
art of persuasion. This is a guy that's
mastered sales and has become one of the
most iconic stock brokers in Wall Street
history. So let's go interview the
legend himself, Jordan Belfort. All
right, you guys, look, we just got out
of the car and we're walking up right
now on Jordan Belfort's place. Look, I'm
pretty sure we are on Star Island right
now, which is one of the richest
neighborhoods. Look, we were already on
one earlier, on to the next man.
Proximity is power. More hands you
shake, the more money you make. Let's go
meet the legend Jordan right now. Come
on.
Here we go. Let's go. All right guys, we
just got into the gate. We are at Jordan
Belfort's house right now and we are
going to be interviewing him any second
now, you guys. Come on.
Hey, how are you? Nice to meet you.
How you doing, Jordan? Nice to meet you,
sir. James Dunmore. How old are you, by
the way? 23 years old. Okay, you're 23.
Hey, I have one rule for all the
interviews, though. What's that?
>> There's no holding back. We're going to
give them the the blueprint on what it
really takes to make it in today's
world. Can we make that happen? I never
hold back, so
>> Let's go. Who am I here with today?
>> Jordan Belfort, the Wolf of Wall Street.
The Wolf himself, yeah.
>> What was the most amount of money you
made in a single day? In a single day,
in cash, 23 million.
It was like in like 4 minutes. What
happened that day? Do you remember?
>> Stop it. It's trading. I I did an IPO.
>> Yeah, I started a brokerage firm when I
was very young and made a ton of money
and uh you know, the story's pretty
public.
>> You're very renowned for your sales
prowess.
>> Right.
>> You mastered the art of persuasion, but
you are an excellent recruiter. What did
you learn about recruiting that you'd
give to an entrepreneur building a
company in today's world?
>> the mistakes people make, they say,
"Well, I'm an entrepreneur. I'm not a
sales person." But every entrepreneur
needs to be a sales person. Bottom line,
right? It's not just selling a product,
you're selling a vision for the future.
You want to have great employees, you
want to have great people that buy into
your vision, right? Well, you have to
communicate that vision to them in a way
that connects to emotionally moves them,
makes them want to take action. Without
that, very difficult. You're going to be
then just recruiting strictly for money
and try to overpay people. They're not
really committed emotionally. They don't
believe in what you're doing. Someone
truly believes in accomplishing a
mission, a vision, they will break
through walls, work twice as hard. But
if you can't communicate that to people
in a way that moves them, well, then
guess what? The vision's a 10 and after
you're done explaining it, they're like,
"Well, that kind of sucks." So, that's
where persuasion comes in and
communication.
>> Do you think everybody's built for
entrepreneurship?
>> Here's what I would say, right? I I
don't think there's a built for or not
built for. It really comes down to your
desire. You know, what do you want out
of life? I don't think everyone has to
be an entrepreneur. Like if you're happy
and what makes you content is something
completely different from that and
you're really not in money, you don't,
you know, measure money and you don't
value it in that way, and that's okay. I
think the problem is when you really do
value money and you want great things
and you want to live a life where you
can have what you want, when you want,
as much as you want, with whoever you
want, all that sort of stuff, right? But
you then don't connect it up with
actually being an entrepreneur and you
think you you're going to get that by
working for a paycheck. Well, that's
very difficult. So, it's like not that
everybody, but I think that anyone that
really wants to live a life of
abundance, it's very difficult to do
that with a paycheck.
>> What is the best financial advice you
would give to the younger generation?
>> The biggest challenge of making money is
finding yourself, getting to that spot
where you actually have a formula to
make money. Then it comes in hard and
fast. I think what people often mistake
with getting rich, you know, I say the
only way to get rich is quickly. I don't
mean through a get-rich-quick scheme.
It's the hard work that you put in. Like
there's certain elements you have to
line up in a business. Often you like
you start something, you think you got a
great plan, looks great on paper, never
works the first time. It's about
pivoting and then trying things and
suddenly that last piece of the puzzle
comes into place and you soar. And then
it's about literally making as much as
you want.
>> you turn a no into a yes? Let's say that
you're trying to get that deal closed
and it's a no. What's your best advice
to somebody trying to get over that
objection, turn a no into a yes?
>> So, I don't really think the job of a
salesperson is to turn no into yes. No
is typically no in a lot of things in
life. You're a young guy, you got to be
careful. No means no, right? But it in
sales, if someone says no, I'm not
interested, have a great day, you know,
I'm not interested in trying to take
somebody who doesn't want what I have or
need what I have. The job of a real
salesperson is to take let me think
about it and turn it into a yes. Let me
call you back. Let me speak to my wife.
Let me talk to my business partner. What
great salespeople do is they take those
and turn them into a yes.
>> There's a saying that money is the root
of all evil. Do you think that money
changes people or does it just amplify
the person who they already are? Anyone
who said that money is the root of all
evil never had any money. That's why
they say it, right? But I think for
sure, always say money is like alcohol.
You know, it amplifies you. It doesn't
change you. It's like you go into a bar,
right? And, you know, someone that's a
really nice person and they get a little
drunk, they're the life of the party,
right? Someone that's an angry, bitter
person inside, when they get drunk,
they're a royal
for that person.
>> Right. That's it. Money is the same way.
>> to challenge you. Take me back to the
most life-changing conversation you ever
had. What's the best advice that Jordan
Belfort received in his life?
>> one would be, you know, when I first got
sober, I had this phenomenal sponsor.
And the the first thing he said to me
was, "Yesterday is history, tomorrow's a
mystery, and today is a gift. That's why
they call it the present."
>> have any regrets? I mean, listen, you
know, I don't live in regrets. Of
course, you know, you say, "Would you
change?" Of course, if I could change
anything, anyone I ever hurt in my life,
I would un-hurt them. But, you can't
live life like that. What you could do
is you can live, learn, and be a better
version of yourself every day, and I
focus on that.
>> question for you, for my audience of 21
million followers, it's only right that
I ask you this. Sell me this pen.
>> [laughter]
>> I've never heard that before. This is a
great one. So, sell me this pen. What it
really is, it's a test for sales people,
right? What typically sales people will
do that don't know how to sell is
they'll just start selling you a pen.
"Oh my god, look at this pen, this black
pen. This is the best pen out there.
Never runs out of ink. I mean, this is
an unbelievable pen." Like,
All right, it's a pen, right? The
question though is, you know, how can I
sell you a pen if I first don't know
what you want? So, the first thing I
would do is I reverse it. So, tell me,
how long have you been in the market for
a pen? Like, are you even looking for a
pen? I don't waste my time trying to
sell things to people that don't need
them or want them. You have amazing
advice, sir. Thank you for your time and
it I I connect with all the millionaires
and billionaires I interview. Could I
get your contact?
>> Yeah, sure. Guys, that's a wrap on
today's video. We just interviewed the
legend, the Wolf of Wall Street, Jordan
Belfort, out here in Miami. But, I need
you to stop right now. Like and
subscribe for amazing content I've got
coming to this channel every single
week. Guys, nobody is bringing you
content like this. But, let's go a step
further. I want to give you direct
access to my billionaire network. Every
single week I host live calls with the
millionaires and the billionaires that I
interview on this channel and it's
inside my school community called the
School of Mentors. It's become the
number one most powerful entrepreneur
community and network in the entire
world. So, I can't wait to see you on
the inside. The link's in the
description to join. With that being
said, we'll see you in the next video.